Finding Aid for Randa Frederickson collection, 1894-1978 and undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Randa Frederickson collection. 1894-1978 and undated
Frederickson, Randa, collector.
0.5 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
861130 Aa 2; UAm
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Randa Frederickson (donor no. 6974 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Randa Frederickson was a resident of Northport, Michigan and a collector of local history materials.
The Frederickson collection includes materials primarily relating to the Norwegian Lutheran settlement in the Northport, Michigan, area. The bulk of the collection consists of letters of the Holden family in Norway to their daughter Elisabeth Holden Talgø. There is also a history of the Garthe-Bahle family. The photographs in the collection are of lumbering activities on North Manitou Island and of schools and road building in Northport, Michigan. Photos and portraits of the Garthe-Bahle-Talgo families are included.
Subjects:
Bahle family.; Michigan--Emigration and immigration.; Garth family; Holden family.; Northport (Mich.); Norwegian Americans--Michigan.; Talgø, Elisabeth Holden.; Norway--Emigration and immigration.; Immigrants--Michigan.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bahle family.; Churches--Michigan--Northport.; Farms.; Laborers.; Lumber industry.; North Manitou Island (Mich.); Northport (Mich.)--Buildings.; Northport (Mich.)--Churches.; Norwegian Evangelical Lutheran Church (Northport, Mich.); Roads--Michigan--Northport.; Schools--Michigan--Northport.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence, mainly from the Holden family in Norway to their daughter Elizabeth Holden Talgo
  - Undated and 1894-1978, 12 folders (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Miscellaneous: religious verse, phrase book, etc. (Box 1)
  - Garthe-Bahle family historical materials (Box 1)
  - Ladies Aid Society, Northport, Michigan: manuscript history and reminiscences of members, compiled 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Leelanau Township Foundation (Northport), ca. 1945 (Box 1)
  - School materials, including valedictory address (Box 1)
- Photographs, ca. 1890-ca. 1969
  - North Manitou Island (mainly logging views) (Box 1)
  - Northport miscellanea, include classroom photographs (Box 1)
  - Garthe-Bahle-Talgo families farms and portraits (Box 1)
  - Northport Evangelical Lutheran Church building, ca. 1910 (Folder 1)